Atharva Niranjan Joshi

<u>atharvanj@gmail.com</u> | +44 – 07587039921 | 20 Sark Walk, London, United Kingdom E163PS | <u>linkedin.com/in/atharvanj</u> | <u>atharvanjoshi.github.io/</u>

SUMMARY

A passionate Forensic Data Analyst working at KPMG UK in the Unstructured Analytics team. Experienced in using Data and Machine Learning for Trader Surveillance. With a Masters in Data Science from Queen Mary University of London, I gained advanced problem solving, programming and AI/ML skills commonly used for data science such as Python and SQL. Commenced my data career as an AI Consultant at Centre for Health Research and Education using Computer Vision to improve Oral Cancer diagnosis. With my extensive career experience, I have also developed strong written and verbal communication skills.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Forensic Data Analyst, KPMG, UK

Oct 2022 – Present

- Actively involved in developing Natural Language Processing (NLP) BERT model using PyTorch and TensorFlow libraries and TF IDF Machine Learning models using SGD classifier for text and audio communications to detect Financial and Non-Financial Misconduct in communications.
- Experienced in using Generative AI for synthetic data generation to create Proof of Concept models and using Gradio to showcase them in an interactive UI.
- Currently working with using Large Language Models (LLM) prompt engineering and fine tuning techniques for models like Llama and GPT to detect specialized risks.
- Used Advanced Microsoft Excel for statistical analysis of data as well as creating appropriate dashboards, model evaluation reports and monitoring data.
- Experienced in working in an Agile Team of developers focused on requirements scoping and deployment schedules and using Git for version control.
- Used Python extensively for data preprocessing such as audio conversion from raw to usable format, speech/voice to text transcription, extracting useful data from noise, deduplication, language translation and logging.
- Experienced in MLOps and involved in creating, deploying, operationalizing and maintaining an end-to-end automated CI/CD ETL data pipeline with all stages of preprocessing, model deployment and prediction, and ingestion into Relativity platform with little to no manual intervention thus improving efficiency.
- Experienced in using Azure Cloud Platform to host machine learning models and language transcription containers on dockers, using Rest APIs for various services, Azure storage explorer for receiving data.
- Used SQL extensively for data storage, management and information retrieval to cater to client requests as well as creating appropriate Stored Procedures to be embedded into Python ecosystem.
- Recognised with 'Employee of the month' award.

Senior Data Analyst, Centre for Health Research and Education, UK

Jun 2021 – Aug 2022

- Researched and applied various Image object detection and classification models like YOLO v4 and R -CNN using Python and Deep Learning frameworks like PyTorch on existing as well as newly created data.
- Coordinated with various medical institutions for obtaining data, managing and storing on Amazon Web Services (AWS) S3 buckets cloud platform for oral cancer research connecting that with a standalone version of LabelImg for annotation.
- Coordinated with medical experts to understand the domain and in creating appropriate datasets.

Systems Engineer, Infosys Limited, India

Sep 2018 – Sep 2020

- Developed applications in Android and iOS using Xamarin.Forms framework based on C# (Object Oriented Programming) and XAML using DevOps on Microsoft Visual Studio.
- Used Azure Active Directory for authentication and Azure APIs for data retrieval and storage.
- Played an important role in the development cycle by implementing complex features, coordinating with my teammates, tracking the progress of each use case development and bug fixes through the Azure DevOps Portal.
- Developed Pilot projects and also presented Proof of Concepts, the working of apps through emulator and walkthrough of codes to the clients through Microsoft Teams.
- Nominated and awarded with a Certificate of Appreciation for my performance in the company.

EDUCATION

IMS ProSchool, India

Master of Science (MSc.), Big Data Science with Industrial Experience

Queen Mary University of London

Percentage: **86.31** (**Distinction**)

Sep 2020 – *Sep* 2022

(**Key Modules**: Natural Language Processing, Applied Statistics, Big Data Processing, Data Mining, Machine

Learning, Deep Learning & Computer Vision, Neural Networks & NLP, Cloud Computing)

Post Graduate Diploma, Data Science

Apr 2019 – *Feb* 2021

Grade: A

(**Key Modules**: *Business Analysis*, *Advanced Machine Learning and Big Data*)

Bachelor of Engineering (B.E.), Information Technology

Jul 2014 – Jul 2018

Savitribai Phule Pune University

Percentage: **63.61** (**2:1**)

(Key Modules: Machine Learning, Cloud Computing, Design & Analysis of Algorithms, IT & Project Management,

Business Intelligence & Advanced Database)

Higher Secondary Certificate (Equivalent to A – Level), Computer Science

Feb 2013 – Feb 2014 Percentage: **71.69**

Maharashtra State Board, India

14 2011 14 2012

Senior Secondary Certificate (Equivalent to GCSE)

Mar 2011 – *Mar* 2012

Maharashtra State Board, India

Percentage: 84.55

SKILLS

Data Science: Python (Pandas, NumPy, Scikit Learn, TensorFlow, PyTorch), SQL, Excel, Relativity, Azure **Languages**: English (Fluent, C1(IELTS)), Marathi (Fluent, Mother Tongue), Hindi (Intermediate)

CERTIFICATIONS

- Infosys Certified Python Programmer and Python Associate
- Natural Language Processing with Classification and Vector Spaces Coursera
- Generative AI with Large Language Models Coursera
- ICA Certification in Financial Crime Prevention
- ICA Certification in KYC and CDD

REFERENCES

Available upon request